{
  "1": {
    "question": "What npm stands for?",
    "answers": {
      "A": "Node Package Manager",
      "B": "New Package Manager",
      "C": "Node Project Manager"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "explanation": "npm stands for Node Package Manager"
  },
  "2": {
    "question": "Which of the following provides in-built events",
    "answers": {
      "A": "throw",
      "B": "callback",
      "C": "events"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "explanation": "Node has multiple in-built events available through events module"
  },
  "3": {
    "question": "True or false: Transform stream is not a type of duplex stream",
    "answer": "FALSE",
    "explanation": "Transform stream is a duplex stream where the output is computed based on input"
  },
  "4": {
    "question": "Which statement execute the code of sample.js file?",
    "answers": {
      "A": "nodejs sample.js",
      "B": "node sample.js",
      "C": "sample.js"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "To execute the file use node followed by the file name"
  },
  "5": {
    "question": "Which of the following module is required for operating system specific operations?",
    "answers": {
      "A": "os module",
      "B": "fs module",
      "C": "None of the above"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "explanation": "Node.js os module provides a few basic operating-system related utility functions"
  },
  "6": {
    "question": "All APIs of Node.JS are",
    "answers": {
      "A": "Asynchronous",
      "B": "Synchronous",
      "C": "Both"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "explanation": "All APIs of Node.js library are aynchronous that is non-blocking"
  },
  "7": {
    "question": "REPL stands for",
    "answers": {
      "A": "Read Eval Point Loop",
      "B": "Read Earn Point Learn",
      "C": "Read Eval Print Loop"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "explanation": "REPL stands for Read Eval Print Loop, and it represents a computer environment like a window console or Unix/Linux shell where a command is entered and system responds with an output in interactive mode"
  },
  "8": {
    "question": "Which of the following module is required to create a web server?",
    "answers": {
      "A": "Web module",
      "B": "Net module",
      "C": "http module"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "explanation": "Node.js provides http module which can be used to create HTTP client of server"
  },
  "9": {
    "question": "What is Node.JS?",
    "answers": {
      "A": "Node JS is a web server",
      "B": "Node JS is a Javascript based framework/platform build on Google Chrome's Javascript V8 Engine",
      "C": "Node JS is a java based framework"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "Node.js provides http module which can be used to create HTTP client of server"
  },
  "10": {
    "question": "True or false: Package.json is present in the root directory of any Node application/module",
    "answer": "TRUE",
    "explanation": "package.json is used to define the properties of a package. It can also be used to update dependencies of a Node application"
  },
  "11": {
    "question": "What is the maximum time span for setTimeout(a,b)?",
    "answers": {
      "A": "24.8 days",
      "B": "18 hours",
      "C": "All of the above"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "explanation": "The setTimeout(a,b) global function is used to run callback A after atleast B milliseconds. It cannot span more than 24.8 days"
  },
  "12": {
    "question": "What is Gulp?",
    "answers": {
      "A": "Gulp is a task runner which uses Node JS to automate & enhance the workflow",
      "B": "Gulp is a web framework for exposing the REST API's",
      "C": "All of the above"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "explanation": "Gulp is a toolkit that helps you automate painful or time-consuming tasks in your development workflow"
  },
  "13": {
    "question": "Node.js runs on?",
    "answers": {
      "A": "Client",
      "B": "Server",
      "C": "Both"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "Node.js is a server-based Javascript"
  }
}
